hitentertainment.com 2019-07-06

# Mattel Online Privacy Statement

##  Mattel Online Privacy Statement 

Updated May 22, 2018

Your privacy is important to us at the _Mattel family of companies_. This privacy statement describes the _information_ Mattel collects from you, through our interactions with you and through our _Mattel Services_, and how we use that information. It also describes what information _third parties_ collect from you, and how we and they use that information. Key terms are italicized and underlined _( like this_) and can be found in the _Definitions_ section. This Privacy Statement provides examples of data we collect, how we use it, and choices you can exercise; these examples may not be exhaustive or exclusive.

This statement applies to _Mattel Services_, including _Mattel Sites_, apps, mobile apps, online services, and connected products. _Mattel Sites_ are also subject to the [MATTEL TERMS AND CONDITIONS](http://corporate.mattel.com/global/terms-conditions-shared.aspx). Other terms, end-user license agreements, or additional rules may apply. Each time you use _Mattel Services_, you agree to this statement. If you don’t agree with all the terms of this privacy statement, please do not use _Mattel  Services_.

We want you and your family to have fun using our services and urge you and your family to follow common sense when disclosing personal information, both through our services and anywhere else.

### Children’s Privacy

We at Mattel pride ourselves on helping bring delight to children around the world and take our responsibility to children seriously. Please visit the  MATTEL CHILDREN'S PRIVACY STATEMENT for specific details on our children's privacy practices.

**Child/children (kid/kids).** Individuals who are not of legal age to consent to the collection and processing of their personal information. ****For most areas of the world, those are individuals under 13. In the European Economic Area (EEA), they are individuals under 16. We adhere to local definitions of “children” for Mattel Services located in jurisdictions where the age is different.

 **Information.** Data we collect. It includes, in alphabetical order:

  *  **Automatically collected information.** Information automatically collected when you use Mattel Services, including information to facilitate your experience and help us understand our visitors, like your device information, information about the network you are using to access Mattel Services (such as preferred language or online sites or services visited before you visit a Mattel Service), and content (including ads) that you see or click on.

  *  **Device information.** Information about the device, browser, or app you are using to access a Mattel Service, such as operating system, browser information, Internet Protocol (IP) address, Universal Device Identifiers (UDID), and similar information.

  *  **Interest or demographic information.** Information about a user’s favorite games, colors, Mattel characters, and similar preferences; or information about a visitor or user, such as gender, age, education, profession, occupation, or other information.

  *  **Location information.** Information that allows you to be precisely located, such as through GPS coordinates on a mobile app.

  *  **Login information.** Information to identify and validate a user to allow access to a Mattel Service. For children, this is usually a user name and password. For adults, this is usually a password plus some personal contact information, like an email address.

  *  **Order information.** Information provided to purchase a product or Mattel Service, including details necessary to fulfill the transaction, such as products ordered, payment information, and personal contact information.

  *  **Payment information.** Credit card numbers or other financial institution-issued information provided to complete a transaction, including (as applicable) _personal_ contact information.

  *  **Personal information.** Information that identifies (whether directly or indirectly) a particular individual, such as the individual’s name, address, email address, device identifier, telephone number, or assigned identifier. When anonymous information is directly or indirectly associated with personal information, this anonymous information also is treated as personal information.

    * For children, personal information also includes photos, video, and audio of the child.

  *  **Personal contact information.** Information that allows us to contact you directly, such as your full name, email address, home address, telephone number, mobile number, etc.

  *  **Survey information.** Answers to surveys or questionnaires voluntarily provided.

  *  **Social sign-on information.** Login information and other information (such as friend lists) from a social network that a user chooses to share with Mattel to access a Mattel Service or Mattel Site.

  *  **Third-party–provided information.** Data shared with the Mattel family of companies through a third party.

  *  **User-generated content.** Information you post or upload, like reviews, comments, videos or pictures, or social media interactions. Read more at User-Generated Content.

 **Interest-based advertising.** Targeted ads for products and services that, based on your activities, are likely to be of interest to you.

 **Mattel family of companies.** When we refer to the Mattel family of companies in this statement, we mean:

  * Mattel, Inc., 

  * Fisher-Price, Inc., 

  * Fuhu/nabi Brands,

  * American Girl Brands, LLC, 

  * HIT Entertainment Limited, and 

  * Mega Brands Inc.

 **Mattel Sites.** Websites offered by the Mattel family of companies. See _ _ Mattel Services.

 **Mattel Services.** All online services offered by the Mattel family of companies, including websites (Mattel Sites), apps, and connected products. Read more at Mattel Services.

 **Third party.** A company unrelated to the Mattel family of companies, including third-party sites that we link to, or third parties that operate online stores or mobile app stores. Read more at Third-PartyPartners and Third-Party Technology Partners.

  *  **Third-party partner or third-party service provider.** A third party that Mattel has engaged to help it provide Mattel Services, including agents, vendors, service providers, and others.

 **Third-party technology partners.** Third parties whose technologies we use to offer content, understand our users, and deliver advertising.

 _Mattel Services_ are online services offered by the _Mattel family of companies_, including:

  *  _Mattel Sites_,

  * Online Stores,

  * Enhanced _Mattel Services_

  * Apps, and

  * Connected products. Check specific connected product FAQS for info on features, who’s responsible for privacy, and what information is collected.

You may have to interface with a _third party_ to make a purchase, download an app, or use a connected product. 

You may have the opportunity to connect an app or connected product through a wireless service.  

| 

 **Mattel Sites**

We offer _Mattel Sites_ that feature games, information, shopping, and other interactive and static activities from the _Mattel family of companies_.

  * Some _Mattel Sites_ or areas of sites are intended for _children_, and some are intended for adults. Learn more about sites for _children_ and specific practices for them at our [CHILDREN’S PRIVACY STATEMENT.](https://www.mattel.com/childrens-privacy-statement)

  * You do not have to share any _personal contact information_ to use most _Mattel Sites_, but most _Mattel Sites_ for adults and teens contain special sections and privileges for members who register.

 **Online Stores**

We offer opportunities to purchase products in our online stores, apps, or through other media or business partners. Online stores are often part of a larger _Mattel Site_.

  * Customers must be over the age of 18 with a valid payment method to make a purchase. 

  * When a customer places an order online, we will send a confirming email message. 

    * We may also send an occasional email featuring a special promotion or product that may be of interest to customers. 

    * Any customer who prefers not to receive an online order confirmation or promotional email may indicate this preference on the online store order form. 

    * If you do receive marketing or promotional emails from us that you would rather not receive, simply follow the “unsubscribe” instructions included in each message.

    * You can also change your communication preferences in [MATTEL COMMUNICATIONS PREFERENCES](https://shop.mattel.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10103&langId=-1&storeId=10151&krypto=l3Pt765QidDDP2g3jxi06RKMxzS8PFh7R3YJ%2FUu2%2FfqKCagvpB4siiQ7%2BN%2Fg0iTEvRzA87bjwnAAxhkkSJDobA%3D%3D) (except for American Girl) or in [AMERICAN GIRL COMMUNICATIONS PREFERENCES](https://www.americangirl.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10601&langId=-1&storeId=10651&krypto=GYgCwdYQAAoeOX8xtiJZwvsEDvjMpXPzd8oKBoM843Hv9VPUgF4ZmPgxnTIuP428MC0xbcymBctaZWk3QybqwA%3D%3D) (for American Girl only).

    * Please note that a request to unsubscribe from marketing or promotional emails will not affect transactional emails (such as those related to a purchase, paid subscription, or product registration).

 **Enhanced Mattel Services**

  * Enhanced _Mattel Services_ may be available to you or on behalf of your _child_ for a monthly or other fee with some _Mattel Services_. 

    * Only a parent or guardian can register _children_ to participate in enhanced subscription _Mattel Services_ or certain community features at _Mattel Services_. 

    * To register your _child_ , we will ask you to provide your _login information_ in addition to your contact details and credit card _information_. 

    * We may offer you the option to be billed automatically for subscription service fees. 

    * If you elect to automatically renew a subscription, we or our trusted _third-party partners_ will retain your registration _information_, including your credit card _information_, so we can process your request.

 **Apps  **

We offer a variety of fun and engaging apps featuring our brands. In some cases, apps may be available through a Mattel Online Store, but most often when you download or purchase an app, or make an in-app purchase, you do so through a third-party mobile application online store. Visit LINKS AND THIRD PARTIES for more information.

 **Please note:** Use of apps may be subject to an End-User License Agreement (EULA) in addition to our standard [MATTEL TERMS AND CONDITIONS](http://corporate.mattel.com/global/terms-conditions-shared.aspx).

 **Connected Products**

Mattel offers parents and _children_ a variety of products that connect to the internet. We sometimes work with _third-party partners_ to offer connected products.

  * Some connected products, like connected baby monitors, are purely for parents’ use. 

  * Use of connected products typically requires downloading an associated app. 

  * Privacy practices for some connected products are the responsibility of a _third party_.  

  * We provide FAQS and other information to help you understand specific connected product features (for example, whether they collect voice or visual data), who’s responsible for privacy, and what _information_ we collect. 

 **Wireless Services**

We may communicate with you on your mobile device. To receive _Mattel Services_ through a wireless connection, visitors must provide their consent and confirm their understanding that they will be charged by their carrier to send and receive messages according to their applicable service plan. You may be asked to reconfirm such agreement. 

  * Standard messaging rates will apply unless otherwise indicated; if premium rates apply, visitors will be notified before registration. 

  * Mattel is not responsible for wireless service charges, such as messaging fees, associated with accessing or connecting to _Mattel Services_

---|---  
  
  * We collect _information_ to allow you to register to use a _Mattel Service_. _Login information_ is often all we need to register you.

  * We collect _personal contact information_.

  * We collect other _personal information_ about you, such as _interest or demographic information_, etc.

  * We collect _user-generated content_ where a _Mattel Service_ gives you that option.

  * We collect _device information_, _automatically collected information_, and _information_ that helps you access _Mattel Services_ (such as _login information_, Wi-Fi network name, etc.).

| 

We collect _information_ from you and about you to provide you with _Mattel Services_. The _information_ we collect depends on the specific _Mattel Services_ involved.

We May Collect from You:

  *  _Login information_.

  *  _Personal contact information_.

  *  _Automatically collected information_.

  *  _Social sign-on information_.

  *  _Order information_.

  *  _Payment information_.

  * A ship-to name and address when you make a purchase and ask us to send it to you or to someone else.

  *  _Location information_.

  * The email addresses, user names, or other _information_ about friends to whom you wish to send an e-card or invite to participate in an offering on _Mattel Services_.

  *  _Information_ about your _child_ (such as your _child_’s _personal information_ and _personal contact information_, including _interest or demographic information_).

  *  _Information_ that allows us to confirm that you are the parent or legal guardian of your _child_, including your age.

  *  _User-generated content_.

  * Wi-Fi network name.

  *  _Survey information_.

---|---  
  
We collect _information_: 

  * that you share voluntarily;

  * to fulfill a transaction; and

  * automatically. 

Please visit [ABOUT COOKIES AND TECHNOLOGIES](https://www.mattel.com/en-us/about-cookies-and-technologies) for more information on technologies used to collect your information automatically.

| 

 **We Collect Information That You Share Voluntarily**

You can use many of our _Mattel Services_ without sharing any _personal contact information_. If you choose, you can share _personal contact information_, _personal information_, _login information_, _interest or demographic information_, or _survey information_ about you or your _child_ with us when you:

  * Register with a _Mattel Service_.

  * Play a game.

  * Use an interactive activity.

  * Make a purchase at one of our online stores (see WE COLLECT ORDER INFORMATION).

  * Order a catalogue.

  * Enter a sweepstakes or contest.

  * Sign up to receive information and offers.

  * Apply for a job online.

  * Respond to a survey or questionnaire.

  * Post _user-generated content_. Special rules apply; read more at USER-GENERATED CONTENT.

 **We Collect Order Information**

When a customer puts an item in a shopping cart, places an order or requests a catalogue online, we collect _order information_ associated with the transaction. This may include _personal information_ about your _child_.

Customers may register when they place orders to conveniently complete an order and place future orders. When registered customers return to the Site to place subsequent orders, they can identify themselves with their _login information_.

 **We Collect Information Automatically When You Access a Mattel Service**

We collect some _automatically collected information_, including _device information_ , to provide you with appropriate _Mattel Services_ or _Mattel Sites_ (for example, in your language) when you use or visit them.  
  
---|---  
  
We collect _information_ from you to serve your needs, manage our content and advertising, operate efficiently, and improve _Mattel Services_ and products.

  * We collect _information_ to do what you ask us to.

  * We collect _information_ to provide you information on _Mattel Services_ and products that you or your _child_ may be interested in.

  * We collect _information_ to support _Mattel Services_ and operations.

  * We collect _information_ to improve _Mattel Services_.

  * We collect _information_to improve our products.

  * We collect _information_ to offer you content.

  * We collect _information_ to advertise to you.

  * We collect _information_ to maintain security.

  * We collect _information_ to protect our legal rights and the legal rights of others.

| 

We collect information:

  * To provide you with _Mattel Services_. 

  * To respond to your requests.

  * To verify you or your _child_’s age.

  * To complete a transaction.

  * To fulfill a transaction.

  * To confirm your order.

  * To give you updates about your order status.

  * To fulfill your free or paid subscriptions.

  * To notify winners in contests and sweepstakes.

  * To send you recommendations on _Mattel Services_ of interest to you or your _children_.

  * To send you recommendations on products of interest to you or your _children_.

  * To send you marketing communications.

  * To send you catalogues.

  * To offer _interest-based advertising_.

  * To analyze and measure the effectiveness of our advertising.

  * To support _Mattel Services_.

  * To understand our visitors.

  * To improve our products.

  * To improve _Mattel Services_.

  * To develop new products. 

  * To develop new _Mattel Services_.

  * To maintain the security, integrity, and quality of our products and _Mattel Services_. 

  * To protect intellectual property.

  * To protect our legal rights.

  * To protect the legal rights of others.

We may work with _third-party partners_, including _third-party technology partners_, for some or all of these purposes. You can learn about some of these _third parties_ by visiting ABOUT COOKIES AND TECHNOLOGIES.

We may combine all _information_ we have collected to better understand your needs, improve _Mattel Services_ and operations, manage content and advertising, send you offers and information, and better serve you.

If under the laws of your region we need to get your consent to collect the _information_for a particular purpose, we will do so at the time we collect the _information_.  
  
---|---  
  
We may share _information_ as follows:

  * We share _information_ we obtain within the _Mattel family of companies,_ and with our _third-party partners_.

  * We share some _personal contact information_ with third parties for marketing purposes with your consent.

  * As is customary with catalogue businesses, we share mailing addresses (but not email addresses) with other catalogue companies whose products and services may be of interest to you. Where required, we obtain your consent first. We give you the opportunity to opt out.

  * If you provide _social sign-on information_, Mattel shares _information_ with your social network.

  * We share _information_ about usage and interests that we obtain through cookies and technology with _third-party technology partners_, and obtain consent if required by applicable law. Find out more about Your Choices and Controls.

  * We share any _information_ (including _personal information_) we obtain as necessary to satisfy a legal request or subpoena, protect property or personal safety, when a Mattel business is bought or sold, or as otherwise permitted or required by law.

| 

We share _information_ that we obtain within the _Mattel family of companies_, and with our _third-party partners_ for them to fulfill their tasks on our behalf.

Except as described in this Privacy Statement, we do not share _personal contact information_ that we receive online from or about _children_ with other companies outside the _Mattel family of companies_ for their direct marketing purposes.

 **Sharing with Our Third-Party Partners**

We may share your _information_ with a variety of _third-party partners_. They:

  * Provide database and server maintenance and security.

  * Help us manage transactions.

  * Help us process and fulfill orders or requests.

  * Help us analyze our offerings.

They also provide other similar services to the _Mattel family of companies_. We require third-party partners that access _information_ to safeguard the _information_.

 **Sharing with Third Parties for Marketing Purposes**

  * We share certain names and mailing addresses of catalogue recipients with _third parties_ whose catalogues may be of interest to you. Where required, we obtain your consent first. You can opt out at any time.

  * With your consent, Mattel shares _personal contact information_ with outside companies that offer products or services that may interest you.

  * We will remove your name from the list we provide to outside companies if you contact us. Please visit [Mattel Communications Preferences](https://shop.mattel.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10103&langId=-1&storeId=10151&krypto=l3Pt765QidDDP2g3jxi06RKMxzS8PFh7R3YJ%2FUu2%2FfqKCagvpB4siiQ7%2BN%2Fg0iTEvRzA87bjwnAAxhkkSJDobA%3D%3D) (except for American Girl) or [American Girl Communications Preferences](https://www.americangirl.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10601&langId=-1&storeId=10651&krypto=GYgCwdYQAAoeOX8xtiJZwvsEDvjMpXPzd8oKBoM843Hv9VPUgF4ZmPgxnTIuP428MC0xbcymBctaZWk3QybqwA%3D%3D) (for American Girl only).

 **Sharing with Social Networks**

If you provide _social sign-on information_ to log in to a _Mattel Service_ or _Mattel Site_, _information_ is shared with your social network, such as the fact that you logged in to a Mattel Service or Mattel Site, or your activity on the _Mattel Service_ or _Mattel Site_. We may send messages via the social network to communicate with you.

 **Sharing with Third-Party Technology Partners**

We share _information_ about usage and interests that we obtain through cookies and technology with _third-party technology partners_, and obtain consent if required by applicable law. Find out more at Your Choices and Controls.

 **Sharing to Protect Legal Rights and Fulfill Legal Obligations**

If Mattel believes that anyone’s behavior in any _Mattel Service_ may damage us, _Mattel Services_, or any person or property, we may disclose _personal information_ to prevent such harm. In that case, we might try to identify the wrongdoer, contact them, or bring legal action against them.

We may disclose _personal information_ if we believe that the disclosure is required or permitted by law, or in response to a legal request or subpoena.  
  
---|---  
  
  *  _Mattel Services_ may link to or use other content from the internet. We do not control the data collection practices or terms of use of any _third-party_ site. The _third party_’s privacy policy and terms of use apply to those sites.

  * Your computer or mobile device settings may allow you to block or partially block other content, but those settings may not be effective in all cases.

  * You may be able to order or register through a _third-party_ vendor. The _third party_’s privacy policy and terms of service apply to activity conducted with the third-party vendor.

  * We work with _third-party partners_ to offer _Mattel Services_.

| 

 **Other Sites We Link to**

 _Mattel Services_ may connect with other content from the internet that we do not control.

  * We may link to social media sites or sites that sell our products.

  * We may link to other _third-party_ sites or services that we think you may find of interest.

  * We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policy and terms of use of the third-party providers, as they are not covered by this Privacy Statement, and Mattel is not responsible for them.

  * You may be able to alter settings on your browser, device, or other software to block those third parties. Sometimes those settings may not be effective.

 **Third-Party Vendors**

When you place an order or register on a _Mattel Service_ where transactions are handled by a third-party vendor (for example, PayPal), those transactions are conducted through the vendor’s website.

  * You should be sure to review the _third party_’s website terms and conditions and privacy policy before submitting any _personal information_ or engaging in any transactions through the third-party site.

  * Mattel is not responsible for any transactions made with third parties, or for their content, terms and conditions, or privacy policies.

 **Third-Party Partners and Third-Party Technology Partners**

  * We work with _third-party partners_ to offer _Mattel Services_. We ask them to carefully handle _information_ that is entrusted to them.

  * We also work with _third-party technology partners_ to provide content, understand our users, and deliver advertising on our _Mattel Sites_ and on _third-party_ sites. Read more at [About Cookies and Technologies](https://www.mattel.com/en-us/about-cookies-and-technologies), and find out about tools are available to help you control some of these technologies at the [Third-Party Technology List](https://www.mattel.com/sites/mattel_mattelcom/files/2018-07/2018-07-25%20Mattel%20CLEAN%20List%20of%20partners%20%20tools.pdf) and the [Mobile Third-Party Technology List.](https://www.mattel.com/sites/mattel_mattelcom/files/2019-01/Mobile%20Third%20Party%20cookies%20and%20other%20technologies%201-15-19.pdf)

 **Mobile App Stores**

  * You may be required to register with and log onto a _third party_ mobile app store before you can download or purchase a Mattel app or make in-app purchases using a Mattel app.

  * When downloading a Mattel app, or using a Mattel app with online features through your mobile platform, the app provider will typically also collect certain device and app-related _information_. Mattel does not control the requirements or policies of app stores; you should review the privacy policy and terms of use of the mobile app stores before downloading or using any app and check your device settings for control options.

---|---  
  
 **Your Choices**

We respect your choices about receiving promotional offers and updates from us. You can change what communications you get from us in [Mattel Communications Preferences](https://shop.mattel.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10103&langId=-1&storeId=10151&krypto=l3Pt765QidDDP2g3jxi06RKMxzS8PFh7R3YJ%2FUu2%2FfqKCagvpB4siiQ7%2BN%2Fg0iTEvRzA87bjwnAAxhkkSJDobA%3D%3D) or in [American Girl Communications Preferences](https://www.americangirl.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10601&langId=-1&storeId=10651&krypto=GYgCwdYQAAoeOX8xtiJZwvsEDvjMpXPzd8oKBoM843Hv9VPUgF4ZmPgxnTIuP428MC0xbcymBctaZWk3QybqwA%3D%3D).

You can make choices about your _personal information_ that Mattel has in the [Mattel GDPR Choice Portal](https://privacy.mattel.com/) (except for American Girl) or the [American Girl GDPR Choice Portal](https://privacy.americangirl.com/) (for American Girl only). Parents can access their _children_ ’s _personal information_ and make choices about it using the [Parental Access Form](http://corporate.mattel.com/ParentalAccessForm.pdf).

 **App Controls**

Your device may allow you to block or manage push notifications, _location information_ , in-app purchases, or ability to access the web.

| 

 _Your Choices About Communications_

If you want to stop receiving promotional updates or product information at any time, you can change your [Mattel Communications Preferences](https://shop.mattel.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10103&langId=-1&storeId=10151&krypto=l3Pt765QidDDP2g3jxi06RKMxzS8PFh7R3YJ%2FUu2%2FfqKCagvpB4siiQ7%2BN%2Fg0iTEvRzA87bjwnAAxhkkSJDobA%3D%3D) or your [American Girl Communications Preferences](https://www.americangirl.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/AjaxLogonView?catalogId=10601&langId=-1&storeId=10651&krypto=GYgCwdYQAAoeOX8xtiJZwvsEDvjMpXPzd8oKBoM843Hv9VPUgF4ZmPgxnTIuP428MC0xbcymBctaZWk3QybqwA%3D%3D). Our mailings and email will also include information on how to opt out. Email opt-out requests will be processed in 10 business days. Postal mailing opt-out requests may take longer.

 _Your Choices and Control About Your Personal Information_

If you want to access, update, or delete your _personal information_ ; withdraw your consent to our collection or use of your _personal information_; object to our processing of your _personal information_; or request a portable copy of your _personal information_, you can access the [Mattel GDPR Choice Portal](https://privacy.mattel.com/) (except for American Girl) or the [American Girl GDPR Choice Portal](https://privacy.americangirl.com/) (for American Girl only). You can use these portals to make choices about information that Mattel has about you.

 _Parental Controls_

Parents can access their children’s data and make choices about how Mattel uses that data, including updating or deleting the data, using the [Parental Access Form](http://corporate.mattel.com/ParentalAccessForm.pdf).

 _App Controls_

With apps, you may be able to:

  * Use your built-in mobile device settings and controls to:

    * Manage push notifications.

    * Manage _location information_.

    * Manage or restrict in-app purchases.

    * Manage camera, microphone, and photo reel, album, or gallery permissions.

  * Block navigation to the web by turning off network access on the device or turning off the browser.

Access to or availability of controls may vary depending on your device.  
  
---|---  
  
We strive to maintain the security of _information_ but cannot guarantee that _information_ security measures are failure proof.

| 

We strive to protect the _information_ you provide to us when you use our _Mattel Services_ through commercially reasonable means.

  * We and our agents and affiliates use encryption or other security measures to protect _payment information_ during transmission and adopt internal procedures to safeguard this _information_ in our systems.

  * We require our _third-party partners_ to follow industry-accepted best practices to safeguard _personal contact information_ and other _information_ they handle.

  * Please be aware that while we work hard to protect your _information_, no method is 100% secure.

  * We cannot guarantee security procedures of third parties.

  * We recommend that you learn about and use tools, habits, and practices to protect the security of you and your family. For example, we recommend that you use unique passwords that are hard for others to copy or guess.

---|---  
  
  *  _Mattel Services_ and servers are governed by U.S. law, which may have different privacy requirements for your _information_ from where you live.

  * Our servers are in the United States and the United Kingdom. We may also use cloud services.

  * We use Standard Contractual Clauses for transferring _personal information_ from the European Economic Area (EEA) or Switzerland to non EEA-countries.

  * Your use of _Mattel Services_ is subject to the collection, transfer, processing, and use of data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

  * Do not use _Mattel Services_ if you do not agree to this Privacy Statement.

| 

 _Mattel Services_, the servers that make _Mattel Services_ available, and databases where we house _information_ may be located in countries that may have privacy laws that differ from where you live.

  * Servers for _Mattel Services_ are located in the United States and the United Kingdom. We may use cloud services whose servers may be anywhere in the world.

  * For users whose use of _Mattel Services_ results in the transfer of personal _information_ from the European Economic Area (EEA) or Switzerland to non-EEA countries, we rely on Standard Contractual Clauses.

  * By using _Mattel Services_, the transfer, collection, processing and use of data will occur as specified in this Privacy Statement, our [Mattel Terms and Conditions](http://corporate.mattel.com/global/terms-conditions-shared.aspx), and any other terms provided at the time of collection.

  * If you do not consent to the transfer, collection, processing, or use of this data according to these terms, do not use the Services.

---|---  
  
  * We will update this Privacy Statement from time to time by posting it here.

  * We will not change how we handle previously collected _information_ without providing notice. If applicable, we will also obtain your consent. 

| 

We may update our Privacy Statement from time to time. When this happens, we will notify you of the new provisions by posting them on our _Mattel Sites._

  * We will not make a material change in how we handle _personal information_ previously collected without notice and, as required, with consent. 

---|---  
  
If you are a resident of California, you have certain rights. 

| 

Under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, _information_ about _third parties_ with whom we have shared _information_ about you for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of _personal information_ shared. To make such a request, please complete and send us the [Privacy Request Form](http://corporate.mattel.com/CAShineTheLightActRequestForm.pdf). We will respond to you within 30 days of receiving such a request.  
  
---|---  
  
If you are a citizen of a European Economic Area (EEA) Member State and you have questions about Mattel’s privacy practices, you can contact supervisory authorities in the EEA to share your concerns.

| 

If you are a citizen of a European Economic Area (EEA) Member State, you can exercise your rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) by visiting the [MATTEL GDPR CHOICE PORTAL](https://privacy.mattel.com/) or the [AMERICAN GIRL GDPR CHOICE PORTAL.](https://privacy.americangirl.com/) You can also contact supervisory authorities within the EEA, including in your own Member State, about concerns you have related to Mattel’s privacy practices. The lead supervisory authority for _Mattel Services_ offered in the EEA is the Dutch Data Protection Authority, the Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens.  
  
---|---  
  
We do not take action to respond to do not track signals available on some browsers.

| 

Some web browsers may transmit “do not track” signals. Web browsers may incorporate or activate these features differently, making it unclear if users have consciously activated them. As a result, at this time we do not take steps to respond to such signals. You can manage your cookie preferences using your own browser settings to accept or block some or all cookies or receive notice so you can consent to cookies. If you block all cookies some features of _Mattel Sites_ may be unavailable to you.  
  
---|---  
  
 _Mattel Services_ that feature the following seals are certified by the respective organizations:

  * Entertainment Software Rating Board Privacy Certified Program

  * kidSAFE Seal Program

| 

 _ESRB Privacy Certified Program_  
Mattel is a valid licensee, and participating member in good standing of the [ENTERTAINMENT SOFTWARE RATING BOARD’S PRIVACY CERTIFIED PROGRAM ](http://www.esrb.org/privacy/faq.aspx#10)(“ESRB Privacy Certified”). ESRB Privacy Certified seals appear on the _Mattel Services_ that participate in the program. The ESRB’s Privacy Certified Program is designed to ensure that our _information_ disclosure practices are responsible and appropriate.   
To help protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and have had _Mattel Services_ where the ESRB Privacy Certified seal is posted reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Certified to meet established online _information_ collection, use, and disclosure practices. As a licensee of this privacy program, we are subject to audits of services and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB.  
If you believe that we have not responded to your privacy-related inquiry about a _Mattel Service_ or _Mattel Site_ that bears an ESRB Privacy Certified seal or your inquiry about a _Mattel Service_ or _Mattel Site_ has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB at http://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.aspx or: 

ESRB  
Attn: Privacy Certified Program  
420 Lexington Avenue, Suite 2240 New York, NY 10170  
privacy@esrb.org

ESRB is not affiliated with Mattel and cannot help you with non-privacy-related issues. 

 _Kidsafe Seal Program_  
Some Mattel connected products bear the kidSAFE Seal. This means that the products and _Mattel Services_ that bear the kidSAFE Seal have been independently reviewed, certified, or listed by kidSAFE to meet certain standards of online safety or privacy, and that Mattel and any technology partner it has partnered with are authorized to display the kidSAFE Seal in connection with that product.  
If you have an inquiry about a _Mattel Service_ or product that bears the kidSAFE Seal, please contact kidSAFE at https://www.proprofs.com/survey/t/?title=xs7un.  

---|---
